Damn, where did he go?
可恶 跑哪儿去了
Over there.
在那里
Time to end this game, right?
游戏该结束了吧
Mr. Thief.
小偷先生
Yeah.
是啊
It's already too dark to play hide-and-seek.
天已经黑了 不适合玩捉迷藏了
Great detective.
大侦探
I am a high school detective, Shinichi Kudo.
我是高中生侦探工藤新一
When I went to the amusement park with my childhood friend, Ran Mouri,
一次我和青梅竹马的同班同学毛利兰去游乐园玩时
I witnessed a suspicious transaction made by a man in black.
正巧目击到一群黑衣男子在进行可疑的交易
I was too preoccupied with watching at that time,
当时我只顾着偷看交易
and didn't notice another accomplice approaching from behind.
竟没有注意到另一人正从身后靠近
He made me take the poison by force.
我被那人灌下了毒药
When I woke up,
醒来后发现
my body became smaller.
身体居然变小了
If those guys knew that Shinichi Kudo was still alive,
如果让那些家伙知道工藤新一还活着的话
they would definitely come after me,
他们一定会来追杀
even the people around me would get involved.
甚至我身边的人也会跟着遭殃
At the suggestion of Professor Agasa, I concealed my true identity.
我听从阿笠博士的劝告决定隐姓埋名
When Ran asked for my name,
当被小兰问及名字的时候
without time to think it over,
情急之下
I took the name of Conan Edogawa.
我化名为江户川柯南
In order to collect information about those guys,
为了收集有关那些家伙的情报
I moved in with Ran whose father is a detective.
我被寄养在了爸爸是侦探的小兰家里
The culprit is you!
犯人就是你
This middle-aged man is Kogoro Mouri,
这位大叔就是毛利小五郎
Ran's father.
是小兰的父亲
He is now a famous detective who scares the hell out of the bad guys,
现在是个让人闻风丧胆的名侦探
known as Sleeping Kogoro.
人称沉睡的小五郎
If you ask me why...
这其中的原委…
I guess I don't even need to tell you.
不用我说明大家也知道了吧
(Stun-Gun Wristwatch) (Voice-Changing Bowtie) These two gadgets are invented by Professor Agasa.
这两个发明是阿笠博士的杰作
In order to help the smaller me,
阿笠博士为了帮助被缩小的我
Professor Agasa invented many interesting gadgets one after another.
接连发明了许多有趣的玩意儿
Especially this belt that can shoot a soccer ball no matter where I am.
尤其是这个无论何处都能射出足球的皮带
Just press the button on the belt buckle,
只要按下皮带扣上的按钮
the soccer ball will expand and shoot out. It's absolutely a superb invention.
足球就会膨胀射出 是个超一流发明
But then again,
话说回来
Other than Professor Agasa,
知道我真实身份的
there are others who know my true identity.
除了博士以外还有其他人
My father and mother.
我的老爸和老妈
Heiji Hattori, a high school detective from Kansai,
关西的高中生侦探服部平次
and Ai Haibara, who goes to the same elementary school as me.
以及跟我就读同一小学的灰原哀
She and her sister Akemi Miyano
她和她姐姐宫野明美
used to work with those men in black.
过去都是黑衣人的同伙
But the Black Organization killed Akemi Miyano.
不过宫野明美被组织杀害了
This made Ai Haibara determined to resist.
对此予以反抗的灰原
When she escaped from the organization,
当她逃出组织时
she took the same drug as me.
吞下了跟我一样的毒药
After that, her body has also become smaller.
因此身体也缩小了
There is another person,
另外还有一个人
Kaitou Kid.
怪盗基德
There is not yet a clear winner between us.
我跟他之间尚未分出胜负
I swear on my honor as a detective
赌上侦探的名誉
that I will definitely bring him to justice this time.
这次一定要将他绳之以法
Although my body is smaller, my mind is still flexible.
身体虽然变小头脑依旧灵活
I am the famous omniscient detective.
无所不知的名侦探
Only one truth will prevail!
真相永远只有一个
I see.
原来如此
So this is the advanced notice sent by Kiddo?
请将VOBSUB设置为Extend to 4:3(扩展为4:3) 以免字幕重叠或遮挡画面
Yes.
是的 请将VOBSUB设置为Extend to 4:3(扩展为4:3) 以免字幕重叠或遮挡画面
This morning, I found it on the balcony of my apartment
今天早上在我家公寓的阳台 请将VOBSUB设置为Extend to 4:3(扩展为4:3) 以免字幕重叠或遮挡画面
along with a large bouquet of roses.
跟一大束玫瑰花放在一起 请将VOBSUB设置为Extend to 4:3(扩展为4:3) 以免字幕重叠或遮挡画面
The guy is still as pretentious as usual.
那家伙还是一样爱装模作样
Romeo, Juliet,
Romeo(罗密欧) Juliet(朱丽叶)
Victor, Bravo.
Victor(征服者) Bravo(喝彩)
While the 26 letters soar around,
在26个字母的纷乱飞舞中
I am going to steal your Jewel of Destiny
我将前来拜领命运的宝石
Kaitou Kid.
怪盗基德
And there is a playing card cut in half.
还有一张分成两半的扑克牌啊
Please enjoy it.
请用
Thank you.
谢谢
What do you think, Mr. Mouri?
您有何看法呢 毛利先生
Well...
这个嘛
What is the Jewel of Destiny?
什么是命运的宝石
He means this one.
他指的是这个
It's beautiful.
好漂亮啊
This is the star sapphire, right?
这是星蓝宝石吧
Yes.
是的
The three crisscrossing streaks on the surface
浮现在表面纵横交错的三条线
represent faith, hope and fate.
象征信赖 希望 命运
It's called the Jewel of Destiny.
被称为命运的宝石
Oh, I see.
原来如此
It really lives up to its name.
真是名不虚传啊
It comes from Josephine, who loved sapphires deeply.
它来自于深爱蓝宝石的约瑟芬
That's why I used this sapphire for this play.
所以这次演出也用了这颗蓝宝石
Play?
演出
I know it.
我知道
The newly opened Universal Theater in Shiodome
在汐留新开的宇宙剧场
is now staging the theater play "Josephine".
现在正在上演舞台剧《约瑟芬》
Josephine?
约瑟芬
She was the first wife of Napoleon.
就是拿破仑的第一任王妃
She was also known for her love of collecting roses.
她也是个有名的玫瑰收藏家
So that's it.
原来如此
That's why he sent roses.
所以才送玫瑰花啊
That's right, little kid.
没错 小弟弟
You do know a lot.
你知道得真不少
He knows a lot of this kind of boring stuff.
他就知道这些无聊的东西
Romeo, Juliet,
Romeo Juliet
Victor, Bravo.
Victor Bravo
Juri-san.
树里小姐
What?
什么事
Is Romeo and Juliet being staged
在您登台演出的那个剧场中
in the theater where you are performing?
现在有上演《罗密欧与朱丽叶》吗
Yes.
是的
I didn't perform in that play,
虽然我没参加演出
but that was the first play staged when the theater opened.
不过那刚好是剧场启用时的首次公演
Is there a problem?
有什么问题吗
I figured it out.
我明白了
Really?
真的吗
This advanced notice from Kiddo
基德送来的这封预告函
contains 3 Ws and 1 H.
暗含3个W和1个H
That means:
也就是说
Who, When, Where, and How.
谁(Who) 何时(When) 何地(Where) 如何(How)
It implies these four elements
暗示了这四个内容
I see.
原来如此
Are you sure?
没问题吧
First is who.
首先是谁
An idiot can see that it's Kiddo.
这不用说也知道是基德
Then where?
接着是何地
The theater where Romeo and Juliet are staged,
上演罗密欧与朱丽叶的剧场
that is, the Universal Theater.
也就是宇宙剧场
And then, when?
然后是何时
The advanced notice mentioned Bravo,
预告函上提到喝彩
so it should be when the audience is cheering.
所以应该是接受观众喝彩之时
And finally, how?
最后是如何
The letter mentioned the Victor,
信中提到征服者
which refers to Napoleon,
指的就是拿破仑
that is, the character that Kiddo is going to dress up as.
也就是指基德打算装扮的人物
And the playing card on the advanced notice.
还有预告函上的扑克牌
The card cut in half represents the V of victory.
分成两半的扑克牌代表胜利的V
So, when your theater play "Josephine" ends
所以怪盗基德会在你所演出的舞台剧《约瑟芬》
and the audience cheers for it,
落下帷幕接受观众的喝彩时
Kaitou Kid will suddenly appear in the guise of Napoleon and steal the ring.
假扮成拿破仑现身盗走戒指
Bravo!
精彩
Bravo, Mouri-san!
太精彩了 毛利先生
No wonder they call you the famous detective!
不愧是名侦探
You flatter me.
哪里 哪里
Uncle Mouri!
叔叔
What does he mean by the 26 letters soar around?
26个字母纷乱飞舞是指什么啊
Idiot, why don't you count the letters of the alphabet?
笨蛋 数一数上面的英文字母
Romeo, Juliet, Victor, Bravo.
Romeo Juliet Victor Bravo
26 letters in total, right?
总共是26个字母吧
Oh, I see.
是这样啊
By the way, Juri-san,
对了 树里小姐
when is the "Josephine" going to end?
《约瑟芬》的公演到何时为止
Today is the last day.
今天是最后一天
So Kiddo will be in...
这么说基德就会在…
What's wrong with you this time, little brat?
臭小子 这次又怎么了
But it's strange.
可是好奇怪哦
Look, there are only 22 letters here.
你看 这里只有22个字母
How can it be?
怎么可能
It's true. I counted it too.
是真的 我也数过了
Including the exclamation point, there are still 3 letters missing.
加上惊叹号还差3个字母
Then Kiddo must have made a mistake.
那一定是基德数错了
Anyway,
总而言之
Kiddo will definitely come to steal the jewel tonight.
基德今晚肯定会来偷宝石
Yes, I see.
是的 我明白了
Then there is something I need to ask you.
那么有件事想跟您商量
Although I'll contact the police afterwards.
当然我随后就会去和警方联系
Could you please come to the theater tonight
能否请您今晚亲临剧场
to stop Kiddo from stealing the jewel?
阻止基德偷走宝石
No problem.
没问题
I, Kogoro Mouri,
在下毛利小五郎
never turn down a request from a beauty.
从没拒绝过美女的请求
Thank you.
谢谢你
Hey, Masayo-san, bring it out.
喂 真佐代 快拿出来
Okay.
是的
Here are the tickets for tonight.
这是今晚的票
Welcome to our theater with your friends.
欢迎携友人一同莅临欣赏
Thank you.
谢谢
The 26 letters soar around?
26个字母纷乱飞舞吗
I think 26 letters refer to the English alphabet.
要说26个字母应该就是指英文字母吧
And this playing card.
还有这张扑克牌
It doesn't look like the V of victory.
不太像是胜利的V
It's about to begin. Please stay tuned. Universal.
即将开演 请稍候  宇宙
I'm so excited!
我好兴奋哦
Me too.
我也是
Actually, I've been wanting to see this play for a long time.
其实我早就想来看这部戏了
Hey, Conan.
喂 柯南
Why are you carrying a schoolbag?
你干嘛背个包啊
Looks weird.
真碍眼
Ah, just a little something in there.
啊 一点东西而已
A little? What is it?
一点 什么东西
Did you sneak some snacks in?
是不是你自己偷带了零食来
I'm not you!
我又不是你
Hey, you kids!
喂 你们几个
I'm making an exception to bring you here.
我可是特别带你们来的
Behave yourself.
给我有礼貌点哦
Okay!
是
Sorry, we came along with you too.
真不好意思 连我们也一起跟来了
It's okay.
没什么啦
Mr. Mouri!
毛利先生
Sorry to keep you waiting.
不好意思 让您久等了
Hello, Yaguchi-san.
矢口小姐 你好
It's Yaguchi. Mouri-san is here.
我是矢口 毛利先生来了
Please come in.
请进
Thank you.
打扰了
Welcome, Mouri-san.
欢迎欢迎 毛利先生
Hello.
你好
Sorry I'm not dressed properly now.
很抱歉我现在仪容不整
Natsuki-chan,
夏树
This is the famed detective, Mr. Kogoro Mouri-san.
这位就是大名鼎鼎的毛利小五郎先生
You must have heard of him, right?
你应该听说过吧
My name is Natsuki Sakai.
我叫做酒井夏树
Hello.
你好
It's so big here.
这里好大啊
There are so many flowers.
有好多花呢
Awesome!
帅呆了
I'm sorry.
不好意思
I brought the kids here with me.
承蒙盛邀 我把小孩子们也一起带来了
Nothing. It doesn't matter.
哪里 没关系
Juri-san, are you interested in diving?
树里小姐 你对潜水感兴趣啊
Yes, I just started learning that recently.
是啊 最近才刚开始学
Want to go with me some day?
改天要不要一起去
Sure, anytime.
好啊 一定奉陪
I remember you've never dived before.
你明明没潜过水
Ran-kun, what did you say?
小兰 你刚刚说什么
Nothing.
没说什么
There are so many cosmetics.
有好多化妆品哦
Yeah.
是啊
This is called foundation, right?
这就叫做粉底吧
There are...
光是粉底就有
1, 2, 3, 4...
1 2 3 4
5 types of foundations.
有5种呢
5 types... So many?
有5种这么多
Hey!
喂
Little girls.
小妹妹们
It's a little too early for you to be interested in makeup, isn't it?
对化妆感兴趣还早了点吧
Kids should behave like kids.
小孩就要有小孩的样子
Got it?
知道了吗
Alright.
知道了
Coming.
来了
Masayo-chan.
真佐代
Narusawa-san!
成泽先生
I heard Mouri-san is here.
听说毛利先生来了
Mouri-san?
毛利先生
You are the famous detective Kogoro Mouri, right?
您就是名侦探毛利小五郎先生吧
My family name is Narusawa. I admire you very much.
敝姓成泽 非常崇拜您
You flatter me.
不敢当
Are you playing Napoleon in this play?
你这次是演拿破仑吗
Yeah. Sorry I came here in costume.
是的 很抱歉穿着戏服就过来了
Anyway, let me introduce you.
对了 我来介绍一下
This is Tenko Tajima who plays Josephine's best friend, Theresa Tallien.
她是饰演约瑟芬的好友泰瑞莎·塔利安的田岛天子
Nice to meet you.
请多指教
This is Isao Shinjo who plays Josephine's lover, Hippolyte Charles.
这位是饰演约瑟芬的情人伊波利特·夏尔的新庄功
Hello.
你好
And then this is the stage manager who also plays Josephine's patron
然后是舞台监督 兼出演约瑟芬的资助人
Barras de Boer...
巴拉斯·德·波尔的…
My name is Toru Ban. Nice to see you.
我叫做伴亨 请多指教
Me too.
请多指教
Now everyone's here, right?
大家都到齐了吧
Inspector Nakamori.
中森警官
Hello, Mouri-san.
你好 毛利先生
It's been a long time...
久违--了
Thank you so much for last time...
上次很谢--谢你
You're too polite. I'm the one who should thank you.
哪里 我才该谢--谢你呢
Are they really themselves?
都是本人吗
I mean them.
我说他们
Indeed.
的确
Kiddo often gets in by pretending to be a relevant person.
事先扮成相关人士是基德常用的手段
Maybe he's already among them.
说不定他已经混在这些人当中了
I almost forgot.
差点忘了
This time I brought a person to assist with the investigation
这次我特地带了个人来协助调查
Actually, I said I wouldn't need him,
不过我本来说是用不着的
but that stupid Megure...
该死的目暮却…
No, I mean Inspector Megure... He strongly recommended him.
不不 是目暮警官强力推荐他
Come on in.
进来吧
Hello, everyone, I'm Shinichi Kudo.
大家好 我是工藤新一
Shinichi?
新一
Kudo-kun?
工藤
Kai... Kai...
怪…怪…
So it's this brat.
原来是这个臭小子
Isn't Shinichi Kudo...
工藤新一不就是…
that famous high school detective?
那个很有名的高中生侦探吗
Kai... Kai...
怪…怪…
Who is he?
他是谁啊
What are you talking about?
你在说什么啊
He's Ran-onee-san's boyfriend.
他是小兰姐姐的男朋友
No such thing.
才不是呢
It's her husband.
是她老公才对
Sonoko!
园子
He is Kaitou Kid!
他是怪盗基德
This guy is not Shinichi-ni-chan!
这个人不是新一哥哥
He's Kiddo in disguise!
是基德假扮的
Kiddo in disguise?
基德假扮的
How can you be so sure?
你怎么知道
Because I'm the real...
因为我才是真正的…
The real what?
真正的什么
Nothing.
没事
I see. That's not impossible.
原来如此 那也不是没有可能的
It hurts.
好痛
Inspector Nakamori, please stop it.
中森警官 你别这样啦
What's going on here?
这是怎么回事
I don't know either.
我也不知道
Maybe it's because Kiddo looks like me.
也许是因为基德本来长得就跟我很像
Or perhaps...
或者说
You're the fake.
你才是冒牌货
Come on.
好了
I can be sure that he is real.
可以肯定他是真的
I think we should try to pull each other's face together, just to be safe.
我看就顺便一起拉一下每个人的脸
I don't think it's necessary.
不 没这个必要
My gut is telling me that Kiddo isn't among us.
依我的直觉基德并不在我们之中
But he really is.
明明就在
And I've already had a good idea to catch Kiddo.
而且我已想到抓住基德的妙招
Then, please let me hear your "good idea".
那就请你把那所谓的妙招说出来听听
Maki-san.
牧小姐
If you don't mind, I'd like to ask you all to leave us alone for a moment.
如果不介意的话我想先请其他人回避一下
It's okay, inspector.
没关系 警官
I've finished my makeup.
我也已经准备好了
I'm sorry.
不好意思
I gotta do things my own way.
我要按我自己的方法行事
What did you say?
你说什么
Fine, I don't need a little brat like you to make trouble for me.
那正好 侦探小鬼别来捣乱
Then we're leaving now.
那么我们先告辞了
I look forward to your performance.
期待你们的精彩演出
Hey...
我说
At least you should tell me first when you're back, shouldn't you?
既然回来了 你好歹也先跟我说一声吧
Sorry, sorry.
抱歉
It's because I wanted to see your cute, surprised face.
因为我想看你惊讶的可爱表情
Cute...
可…
How come you've suddenly become so direct?
一回来就那么直接了当啊
Well, I think I'll go check out the roof.
那么 我去屋顶看看好了
Do you want to come with me?
小兰要不要一起去
There seems to be an observation deck on the top floor.
顶楼好像是了望大厅
Ran, just go with him.
小兰 你就去嘛
I'm going too!
我也要去
You stay here.
你不能去
No! I'm going too. Let me go!
要去要去 我也要去
Hey, you little brat!
我说你这小鬼
I'm going too! Take me!
我要去嘛 我要去嘛
All right, then. Let's all go.
好吧 那么大家一起去吧
Great!
太棒了
Do you feel that Conan...
你们觉不觉得柯南
Seems to be a different person in front of Ran-san...
在小兰姐姐面前好像判若两人
It must be because...
一定是因为
he is at that age where he's spoiled.
他正是爱撒娇的年纪
I see.
原来如此
So he's still a little kid.
原来还是个小鬼
Aren't you all?
你们也是吧
How can I leave Kiddo alone with Ran?
怎么能让基德跟小兰独处
Alright, this door is locked too.
好了 这里也上锁了
How's it going?
怎么样了
The doors to the roof are all locked.
通往屋顶的门都上了锁
That means if what I reasoned is correct,
也就是说如果我的推理正确
Kiddo must not come from the roof.
那么基德一定不会从屋顶来
You have a point.
也是啊
But you're already here.
明明已经来了
I'll take care of Conan-kun.
我来照顾柯南
How about you two go out for a walk?
你们两人出去走走吧
No, thanks.
不用了
Besides,
而且
I feel that Shinichi is kind of strange.
我觉得新一怪怪的
He didn't say that kind of thing in the past.
以前的他可不会说那种话
That kind of thing?
那样的话是指
Like I'm...cute or something.
说我可…可爱之类的
That means he's more direct now.
那表示他现在比较坦率
You should be more direct too.
你也应该坦率一点
If you like him, just tell him.
喜欢人家就大声说出来嘛
You idiot!
笨蛋
That's not what I meant.
我不是这个意思啦
Awesome! Awesome!
太棒了 太棒了
Genta-kun, you've been saying "awesome" since we came up here.
元太 你怎么从刚才起一直在说"太棒了"啊
I can't help it.
这也没办法啊
Because this place is really awesome.
因为这里真的是太棒了
What a great view.
这里还真是绝景呢
I just want to say, "it's awesome."
让人只想说"太棒了"
Look.
听吧
Yeah, it's really beautiful.
就是啊 太美了
He's got some nerve
不过他的胆子还真大
to disguise himself as Shinichi.
竟然化身为新一
Because it will be easier to act as me.
因为假扮我行动会比较方便吧
At least it saves us the time to find him.
不过至少省下了找他的时间
Do you know who Napoleon was?
你们知道拿破仑是谁吗
I know that he was a French hero who conquered Europe.
我知道他是曾经征服欧洲的法国英雄
Good.
好的
Consider this a warm-up.
就当作看戏前的准备
I'll give you a riddle related to Napoleon.
我来出个跟拿破仑有关的谜题
Shinichi oni-san, you'll give us a riddle?
新一哥哥要出谜题啊
You're just like Professor Agasa.
好像阿笠博士哟
Don't tell me it's a boring riddle.
不会又是冷笑话吧
My riddle is about history. You can learn something from it!
我的题目可是出自历史 可以学到东西的哦
Do you wanna try, kid?
小鬼也一起想想看吧
Annoying.
真啰嗦
Listen up.
听好
In the land of Napoleon,
在拿破仑的土地上
it is said that two Japanese built a house.
听说有两个日本人盖了房子
Which of the following two people were they?
请问是以下哪两个人呢
1, Huyuno.
1 冬野 (huyuno)
2, Huruno.
2 古野 (huruno)
3, Hukano.
3 深野 (hukano)
Huyuno, Huruno, Hukano.
冬野 古野 深野
Everyone has a "hu" and a "no"
每个人都有个ふ(hu)跟の(no)
I see.
我知道了
Shh, don't say it!
嘘 不能说哦
The difference between the three of them is their middle parts, "yu", "ru" and "ka".
三人不同的是中间的字 yu跟ru跟ka
I see.
我知道了
It's Huyuno and Huruno.
是冬野跟古野
Only Hukano has "ka" in the middle.
只有深野的中间是ka
The middle part "ka" represents China,
中间是ka 就是中华(ka)
so Hukano is Chinese.
所以深野是中国人
What?
干嘛
Did I guess wrong?
我猜错了吗
Your answer is correct, but there is a little problem with your explanation.
答案对了 可是解释有点问题
Do you know there's a famous quote by Napoleon, which goes,
你们知不知道拿破仑的名言是
"Impossible (hakano) is a word not to be found in my dictionary (jisho)."
我的字典(jisho)里没有"不可能"(hukano)这三个字
I've heard it before.
我听过
That's where this riddle comes from.
这个谜题就是从这句名言来的
Land could also be pronounced "jisho".
注:"地所"和"字典"日语同音 土地也称为"地所"(jisho)
The "word (ji)" refers to the name on the door signboard.
"字"可以指门牌上的文字
That is, Hakano is a name not to be found in my land.
注:"不可能"和"深野"日语同音 也就是我的土地没有深野(hukano)二字
So that's why.
原来如此
Actually, what Napoleon said is
其实拿破仑应该是说
"Impossible" is a word to be found only in the dictionary of fools.
"不可能"这三个字只存在于愚人的字典里
That seems to be the correct one.
这好像才是正确的说法
Not bad, Haibara-san.
不愧是灰原
But it's still a boring riddle.
不过这还是冷笑话啊
And...
而且
I don't think I've learned anything from it.
没觉得从这里学到了什么呀
Is that so?
是吗
Josephine, Theresa.
约瑟芬 泰瑞莎
Barras, what can I do for you?
巴拉斯 有什么事吗
General, may I introduce to you
将军 我来替您介绍
Theresa and Josephine.
她们是泰瑞莎跟约瑟芬
And this is...
这位是…
I know who you are.
我知道您是谁
You're General Napoleon Bonaparte.
您就是拿破仑·波拿巴将军
I hear you're very brave.
我听说您非常勇敢
You do me too much honour.
过奖了
General.
将军
Would you like to dance with me?
您愿意跟我跳一曲吗
With pleasure.
乐意之至
I still can't forget
我到现在还念念不忘
those glorious days.
那段光辉的岁月
Bonaparte,
波拿巴
Elba Island.
厄尔巴岛
King of Rome.
罗马王
Ran.
小兰
Is the man next to the Pope your father?
教皇旁边那个人是你爸爸吧
So this is what he called the good idea to catch Kiddo.
缉捕基德的妙招就是这个吗
Haibara.
灰原
Take care of things here.
随后就拜托你了
Okay, just go ahead.
走好
In the name of the Father, Son and Holy Spirit,
我以圣父 圣子 圣灵之名
I take the crown of the Emperor of France...
将象征法国皇帝的王冠…
From now on, I am the Emperor of France, Napoleon I...
我就是法国皇帝 拿破仑一世
Are you okay, kid?
小弟弟没事吧
This is dangerous.
这样很危险喔
I'm fine.
我没事
By the way...
对了…
What's going on here?
发生什么事了
This child suddenly ran out from behind the wall
这个小弟弟突然从转角跑出来
and fell down after hitting me.
跟我撞在一起跌倒了
Are you alright, little kid?
不要紧吧小弟弟
I'm fine.
我没事
But your police baton is really handsome
不过大哥哥的警棍好帅喔
It's much longer than his.
比这位叔叔的长好多
Indeed, it's really long.
真的挺长的
There are many types of police batons.
警棍有好多种类
Under 60 cm in length.
长度60厘米以下
Under 3 cm in diameter.
直径3厘米以下
Under 320 grams in weight.
重量320克以下
Public security committee has strict rules for police batons.
各地的公安委员会对警棍都有严格的规定呢
Isn't your baton a little too long?
大哥哥的警棍会不会太长了点
Why?
为什么
Why is it this long?
为什么会这么长
Because...
因为...
It's not a police baton!
这不是警棍啊
I won't let you run away!
休想逃走
Don't run!
别跑
Damn it!
可恶
Everything in this world,
这世界的一切
the glory, the victory,
荣耀 胜利
and the future, is all mine.
还有未来全是属于我的
Everything belongs to us!
一切都是属于我们的
Go into action as soon as the curtain goes completely down.
大幕完全落下以后就动手
Got it.
我知道
Right now!
就是现在
Everyone, catch Kiddo!
大家抓住基德
He's pretending to be Napoleon.
他假扮成了拿破仑
What is this?
这是干嘛
You didn't think of that, did you, Kiddo?
你没想到吧 基德
Your stupid code
你的白痴暗号
has already been seen through by me, Kogoro Mouri.
早就被我毛利小五郎识破了
It's not like that.
不是啦
I'm not Kiddo!
我不是基德
Cut the crap. Just show me your face.
废话少说快给我现出原形吧
Kaitou Kid.
怪盗基德
It hurts...
好痛…
He's not Kiddo.
他不是基德
Then where is Kiddo?
那么基德在哪里
Time to end this game, right?
游戏该结束了吧
Mr. Thief.
小偷先生
Yeah.
是啊
It's already too dark to play hide-and-seek.
天已经黑了 不适合玩捉迷藏了
Great Detective.
大侦探
You still love to talk nonsense as before.
要逞口舌之利就趁现在吧
It's long overdue for us to have a showdown.
我们也应该一决胜负了
Because your girl is waiting for you to go back and eat dinner.
因为你的情人做好了晚饭正等着你回去吃呢
Conan-kun!
柯南
Dinner is ready!
晚餐做好了
If you don't hurry, I'll eat it all.
再不来就要吃光了
Looks like we'll have a winner today.
看来今天能分出个高下了
Great detective.
大侦探
Indeed.
就是啊
Oh, no.
糟糕
Oh, I see.
原来如此
Hang glider versus paraglider?
滑翔翼对飞行伞啊
You do have some chops.
果然有一套
Is that paraglider
刚才的飞行伞
also the work of Professor Agasa?
也是阿笠博士的作品吗
You have no place to run.
你已经无路可逃了
If you can't fly,
如果不能飞的话
you're just an ordinary thief.
怪盗基德也只不过是个普通的小偷
If you say so, then I'll turn back into the Kaito Kiddo again.
那么我就变回原来的怪盗吧
What's that sound?
这是什么声音
Shit!
糟了
Bye!
再见
Damn it!
可恶
Next up is the weather around the airport.
接着为您播报机场周边地区的天气
First, Hokkaido.
首先是北海道
The weather in Hakodate tonight is rainy.
函馆今晚的天气是雨天
Some areas has heavy thunderstorms.
有些地方会下大雷雨
Hakodate is having a heavy thunderstorm.
函馆下雷雨啊
This weather is really a bummer.
真是扫兴的天气
What if the plane is struck by lightning?
如果飞机被雷击中怎么办
Don't be afraid.
不用怕
The plane will fly above the clouds.
飞机会飞在云上面
But when it lands, it still have to fly under the clouds, right?
可是降落时不是飞到云下面去了吗
Too bad it is raining when I am so beautifully dressed.
难得我今天打扮得那么漂亮 竟然下雨
My grandmother said that if you wear this kind of clothes,
我奶奶说穿这种衣服
when it thunders, your belly button will be stolen by the Thunder God.
打雷时肚脐会被雷公偷走的
Really?
是吗
Then he can just come to steal it, if he wants.
想偷的话就来偷吧
Thank you so much
真是不好意思
for inviting us to your celebration party.
还邀请我们去参加庆功宴
Thanks to your help, the jewel is safe.
因为有各位相助宝石才能平安无事
That's what we should do.
理所应当的
She's right.
就是啊
Don't be too polite. Just go to Hakodate with us.
不用客气一起去函馆玩吧
But why isn't Juri here yet?
不过树里怎么还没来啊
Really.
就是啊
Sorry about that.
不好意思
Natsuki-san is doing her makeup right now
夏树小姐正在帮她化妆
in the car parked in the parking lot.
她们在停车场的车上
Doing makeup?
在化妆啊
It's really hard being a superstar.
当大明星还真是辛苦啊
It's Natsuki-chan who does all the hard work.
辛苦的是夏树
Juri can't leave her for a moment.
树里一刻都离不开她
She's pretty much her personal assistant nowadays.
就连助理的杂务也叫她做
I see.
原来如此
Sorry to keep you waiting.
让各位久等了
You look gorgeous today.
你今天特别漂亮啊
Thank you, Mouri-san.
谢谢夸奖 毛利先生
Seems like everyone has arrived.
大家好像都到齐了
Shinjo-kun is not here yet.
新庄还没来
Shinjo-san is not feeling well.
新庄先生身体不太舒服
He called this morning and said he couldn't make it.
早上打电话来说不出席了
Oh, is that so?
原来是这样啊
It's a pity, isn't it, Juri?
真是可惜啊 树里
What do you mean?
什么意思
Nothing.
没什么
Aren't the other cast members coming?
其他演员不来吗
Of course not.
那当然
What is the use of having those supporting actors here?
叫那些配角来有什么用呢
What was that just now?
刚刚的感觉是怎么回事
If my intuitions are correct,
如果我的直觉没错的话
that guy will definitely show up here.
那家伙一定会来这里
Inspector Nakamori, all personnel are present.
中森警官 全体到齐了
Good.
很好
Team A, take the front.
A组守前门
Team B, take the rear.
B组守后门
Team C, patrol the vicinity.
C组在附近巡逻
Yes, sir!
是
Inspector Nakamori.
中森警官
What is it?
什么事
There are lights inside the villa.
别墅里面有灯光
What?
什么
That's...
那是…
Sky Japan Airlines, leaving for Hakodate.
Sky Japan航空 飞往函馆
Flight 865 departing at 18:15
18:15出发的865班机
is now commencing with boarding procedures.
现在开始办理登机手续
All Flight 865 passengers headed for Hakodate...
搭乘865班机前往函馆的乘客…
Wow!
好棒哦
It's soft and fluffy.
好软的椅子
Not bad, huh?
不错嘛
I feel like a big boss.
好像大老板一样
As far as domestic flights, having a First Class on the second floor
国内航线在二楼有头等舱的
is exclusive to Sky Japan Airlines.
就只有这家Sky Japan航空而已
Hello?
喂
Ran, what's wrong?
小兰 怎么了
You've been looking behind you ever since we got on.
刚刚开始就一直回头看
Nothing.
没什么
Welcome aboard.
欢迎光临
Thank you.
谢谢
She's here.
来了
Who's here?
谁来了
Shh, be quite.
嘘 别说话
Is the seat next to you occupied?
请问你旁边的座位有人吗
Go ahead.
请坐
Eri?
英理
It's you.
是你
Auntie?
伯母
Ah-le-le? Don't tell me you're going to Hakodate too?
咦 莫非妈妈也到函馆
What a beautiful coincidence?
好棒的巧合啊
It's definitely fate that brought you and Dad together again.
爸爸和妈妈果然很有缘
What are you talking about?
你在说什么呀
You were the one who said you were invited by Juri-san to Hakodate
说爸爸受到树里小姐的邀请但去不了
and asked me to accompany you due to your father being busy, weren't you?
叫我来代替的不是你吗
Ran, here you go again!
兰 你又来了
Anyway, why don't you two have a seat?
总之先坐下吧 你们两人
Are you kidding me?
开什么玩笑
Why do I have to sit next to this person?
为什么要坐在这个人的边上
You two...
你们…
Dad!
爸爸
Excuse me, Juri-san.
不好意思 树里小姐
May I sit next to you?
我可以坐在你旁边吗
Sure, please.
请坐
Geez!
真是的
Wait, Mom.
等等 妈妈
Excuse me.
失礼了
Are you Juri-san Maki?
请问你是牧树里小姐吗
I'm Eri Kisaki.
我是妃英理
Thank you for inviting me here.
这次谢谢你的招待
You're welcome.
不用客气
Oh, right...
啊 对了
If the vulgar man sitting next to you
如果坐在你旁边的低俗男子
troubles you with his speech or conduct,
做出什么让你感到不愉快的言行的话
you can ask for my consultation anytime.
随时可以来找我
So you're a lawyer?
原来你是律师啊
I shall be at your service.
那以后再聊了
Sure.
好的
How did things end up being like this?
怎么事情变成这样了
Of course they would.
肯定会变成这样的
I knew it.
我想也是
Sorry to keep you all waiting.
抱歉 让大家久等了
Shinjo-san?
新庄先生
Didn't you say you weren't coming because you were feeling ill today?
你不是说今天身体不适不来了吗
Now I feel much better.
现在身体恢复了
And it's too boring to stay by myself.
而且一个人闲着无聊
So I figured I would join you.
所以还是来参加了
Sorry I'm late.
我来晚了
Princess Josephine.
约瑟芬王妃
Why haven't you done as I said?
为什么不照我讲的做
It's okay.
不要紧
There will be more than enough time once we get there.
到了那里再准备也来得及
Well, have a nice trip.
那么 旅途愉快
We're going.
我们走了
Attention, flight attendants.
现在是机务广播
Please prepare the cabin for departure.
请乘务员变更机门模式
What are you thinking about?
你在想什么
I bet it has something to do with Kiddo.
反正肯定是基德的事
Did he really intend to steal the jewel yesterday?
昨天他是真的想来偷取宝石吗
It's already too dark to play hide-and-seek.
天已经黑了 不适合玩捉迷藏了
Great detective.
大侦探
Besides, he had an overly long police baton.
而且他还带了根过长的警棍
It's too careless a mistake for Kiddo.
就基德而言也太粗心大意了
My seat number is 4K.
我的座位号是4K
K for Kid.
Kid的K哦
Mine is 4J.
我的是4J
J for Jumbo, right?
所以是Jumbo(巨无霸)的J
And mine is 4B.
那我的是4B
That means...
那么就是…
So that's it.
原来是这样
The four words that Kiddo wrote on his advanced notice...
在基德的预告函里所写的四个词
are phonetic codes!
原来是指语音码
Phonetic codes?
语音码
Yeah.
对
They're codes used over wireless communication in order to prevent miscommunication.
在无线电通讯中为了防止听错的通话编码中
R is for Romeo.
R代表Romeo
J is for Juliet.
J代表Juliet
V is for Victor.
V代表Victor
B is for Bravo.
B代表Bravo
And they're also used in the aircraft radio communications.
而且这也运用于飞机的无线电通讯中
SKJ865.
SKJ865
Runway, 16 Left.
跑道 16Left
Taxi in.
准许起飞
Juliet10, Echo10, Charlie10.
请走Juliet10 Echo10 Charlie10
SKJ865, Juliet10, Echo10, Charlie10.
SKJ865 Juliet10 Echo10 Charlie10
In other words, the "26 letters soar around" part
也就是说 在26个字母的纷乱飞舞中
means that he will commit the crime aboard the plane,
是预告将在使用这些字母
where those phonetic codes fly about over the airwaves.
进行空中通讯的飞机上偷取宝石
And it will take place on this flight from Tokyo to Hakodate
而且是在这架从东京飞往函馆的飞机上
Why?
为什么
It could be on the return flight too.
回程飞机也有可能啊
Because of the picture of that playing card?
因为扑克牌的图案吗
Yeah.
没错
The two of spades card was split in half,
黑桃2的卡片被分成两半
which indicates an odd number that is not divisible by 2.
那表示不能被2整除的奇数
Flights from Tokyo to Hakodate,
从东京出发到函馆的飞机
like this flight numbered 865, must be given odd number designations.
和这个865航班一样肯定是奇数
And the return flights are designated even numbers.
而返回的飞机则是偶数
If we think about it this way, we can understand what happened last night.
这样想的话就能明白昨晚的事了
That guy purposely drew my attention to him,
那家伙故意让我察觉
and let me think his plan had failed,
并认为他计划失败
so that he can put everyone off their guard.
好让大家疏忽大意
If that's the case...
如果是这样的话…
Kiddo must be somewhere on this plane,
基德一定在机舱内的某个地方
waiting for a chance to steal the jewel.
伺机夺取宝石
Dear passengers.
各位乘客
Welcome aboard SKJ Airlines.
欢迎搭乘SKJ航空
Is anything wrong?
怎么了
I'm not feeling too well.
总觉得有点不舒服
You must be tired.
一定是累了
Here, Juri, give me your hand.
给 树里 把手伸过来
Here are some vitamin pills.
这是维生素片哦
The captain of this flight is Captain Okoshi.
本机的机长是大越机长
I am your chief cabin attendant, Kondo.
我是乘务长 敝姓近藤
SKJ865. Winds 160 and 10. Clear for takeoff.
SKJ865 风向160度 风速10节 准许起飞
SKJ865. Clear for takeoff.
SKJ865 准备起飞
Runway, 16 Left.
跑道16Left
Take off.
起飞
Check.
确认
V1.
V1
VR.
VR
V2.
V2
Positive.
确认
Gear up.
起落架锁定
My ears feel weird.
咦 耳朵觉得怪怪的
Me too.
我也是
It's because of the change in air pressure.
是气压改变的关系
Just swallow and it'll be fine.
吞口口水就好了
Still weird.
还没好
It didn't work.
没用啊
Then hold your nose and blow.
那就捏住鼻子"哼"地吐一口气
But don't do it too hard.
但不能太过用力
You might get dizzy.
会头晕的
It worked.
好了
Awesome, something came out.
好厉害 有东西出来了
Conan-kun, face forward, all right?
柯南 你朝前面看
You were right! It worked!
真的耶 好了
I guess girls will be girls.
到底还是女孩子
It doesn't look good when you blow your nose, right?
捏住鼻子吐气的样子可不怎么好看
So she wouldn't do that
所以在异性面前…
in front of someone of the opposite gender. Especially someone she likes.
尤其不想让喜欢的人看到
Excuse me, Juri-san.
对不起 树里小姐
Could you please sign this for me as a commemoration?
能不能请你签个名留作纪念
Sure.
好的
Oh no, I forgot my pen
糟了 签名笔忘带了
Maki-san.
牧小姐
Please use this one.
请用这个
Thank you.
谢谢
You can see why I can never live without her.
就因为这个才离不开她呢
What's Dad doing?
爸爸在干什么呢
Don't worry about that superficial man.
别管他 那种轻薄的男人
How about taking this time to introduce me who everyone is?
还不如趁现在你替我介绍一下大家
Okay.
好
I'm sorry.
对不起
Are you alright?
不要紧吧
Here.
给
Thank you so much.
谢谢
Would you like Western or Japanese snacks?
您需要西式点心还是日式点心
No, I'm fine.
不用了
Neither.
两个都不要
Nor any drinks.
饮料也不要
I'll take a beer and a snack.
我要啤酒和小零食
One moment, please.
请稍等
Drinking beer in first class is the best...
坐头等舱喝啤酒最合适不过了…
This rain is horrible.
好讨厌的雨
Indeed.
就是啊
Hopefully everything will be fine.
但愿一切平安
SKJ865, contact Tokyo Control. 118.90.
SKJ865 这是东京塔台 118.90
SKJ865, 118.90.
SKJ865 118.90
Tokyo Control.
东京塔台
SKJ865. Flight level, 390.
SKJ865 飞行高度390
SKJ865, Tokyo Control. Roger.
SKJ865 东京塔台收到
Are you all right, captain?
机长 不要紧吧
It's okay.
没关系
My kid had a fever last night,
昨晚小孩发烧
So I didn't really sleep much.
我没怎么睡
Should I request some coffee for you?
要喝点咖啡吗
Please, if you would.
真是不好意思 那就麻烦你帮我叫一下
Is the ring okay?
戒指没事吗
Yeah.
是啊
But I can't let my guard down yet.
但是还不能大意
Why did she get out this quickly?
怎么那么快就出来了啊
Hey, Masayo-san.
喂 真佐代小姐
Give me chocolates.
给我巧克力
Service for the cockpit?
给驾驶舱提供服务
Very rare for domestic flights.
国内航线中很少见的
It's Misawa.
我是三泽
I've brought the coffee.
送咖啡来了
Please come in.
请进
Sorry for the intrusion.
打扰了
Miss, you can't come in.
小姐你不能进来
It's okay, Misawa.
没关系 三泽
She's your senior.
她是你的前辈
It's been a long time, Captain!
好久不见 机长
It's been almost five years since you resigned, right?
你辞职后差不多过了五年了吧
Seven years.
已经七年了
Has it been that long?
那么久了吗
You too, Nakaya-san. Long time no see.
中屋也好久不见
Hi.
你好
I went to see "Josephine".
我去看过《约瑟芬》了哦
Really? I'm glad.
是吗 我太高兴了
It was wonderful.
那戏很棒呀
Really? Thank you.
真的吗 谢谢
We'll always come in support of you
今后我们也会去为你加油的
Well then, Captain, I'll see you later.
那么机长 后会有期了
Maki-san.
牧小姐
Here's chocolate.
给你巧克力
Thank you.
谢谢
Mouri-sensei, would you like one too?
毛利先生也来一颗吧
Oh, thank you.
那我不客气了
Delicious!
真好吃
How could it be?
怎么会这样
Uncle Mouri, there's an almond scent.
叔叔 有杏仁味
Yeah, it's cyanide poisoning.
嗯 是氰酸中毒
It's the chocolate. There was poison in them!
是巧克力 里面掺了毒药
The chocolates?
巧克力
Dad!
爸爸
It's okay.
不要紧的
If the chocolate you ate was poisoned,
如果叔叔吃的巧克力有毒的话
the symptoms would have already manifested.
早就出现症状了
But why did Juri-san get poisoned?
可是为什么树里小姐会中毒
The captain asked me to tell you,
机长托我转达
in order not to alarm the other passengers,
为了不惊动其他的乘客
please keep it a secret until we arrive at the airport.
在到达机场前请务必保密
Understood.
知道了
But how did the culprit manage to poison Juri-san?
可是犯人到底是如何让树里小姐中毒的呢
It must have been in the chocolates.
还是巧克力吧
Because she collapsed right after eating it.
因为吃了巧克力后马上就倒下了
I think the same way.
我也有同感
No way!
怎么会
I don't know anything about it.
我一点都不知道
I bought this box of chocolates this afternoon from a store in Ginza where we always get them.
这盒巧克力是今天下午从银座的常去的那家店买的
I just opened it!
刚刚才打开的
Right, Natsuki-san?
是不是 夏树小姐
Sorry,
对不起
I wasn't watching clearly.
我没看清楚
Natsuki-sun!
夏树小姐
But you ate one too and nothing happened.
但是你也吃了却平安无事
That means only a portion of the chocolate was poisoned, right?
说明只在一部分巧克力中下了毒吧
If that's the case,
假设是这样的话
then how did the murderer manage to make Juri-san choose the poisoned chocolates?
那么怎样让树里小姐选中那块有毒的巧克力呢
As for which chocolate Juri would choose first,
树里小姐一般会先选哪块巧克力
I think it's natural that her manager would know.
经纪人知道也是应该的
I didn't do it.
不是我干的
Besides, she chooses chocolate randomly every time!
而且她每次吃巧克力的顺序都是不一样的
I remember Juri-san did hesitate over which chocolate to choose.
树里小姐吃巧克力的时候好像犹豫过要选哪一块呢
Shut up! It's none of your business, kid!
烦死了 小鬼给我闭嘴
Anyway, I'll take possession of those chocolates.
总之巧克力先存放在我这里
Okay.
好的
As for the rest, we can only wait until we get to the airport and let the police deal with it.
接下去只能等到了机场交给警方处理了
In order to preserve the crime scene, please move to the seats at the back, everyone!
为了保护现场大家请坐到后面的座位上去
And the front lavatory is now off limits as well.
而且禁止使用前面的厕所
Apart from the chocolate,
说到乘上飞机后
all the things Juri-san ate since she boarded were
树里小姐所吃的东西除了巧克力之外
vitamin pills.
还有维生素片
But it wasn't sure that Juri-san would need to take vitamin pills.
但是无法肯定树里小姐会需要维生素
I got it!
我明白了
I know who the culprit is!
我已经知道犯人是谁了
Dad!
爸爸
Who? Who is the culprit?
是谁 谁是犯人
After the deceased Juri-san boarded the plane,
过世的树里小姐乘上飞机之后
she only ate two types of things.
只吃过两样东西
These two type of things were
这两样东西是
the suspicious chocolates and Tenko-san's vitamin pills.
刚才可疑的巧克力和天子小姐的维生素片
You?
你
I'm sure you all understand now.
想必大家都明白了吧
The culprit who killed Juri-san Maki on this plane...
在飞机内杀害牧树里小姐的犯人
is you, Tenko-san!
天子小姐 就是你
You must be kidding!
开什么玩笑
This is complete nonsense!
简直胡说八道
First of all, I don't even have a motive!
首先我根本没有动机
Are you sure?
是这样吗
Everyone here has a motive to kill Juri-san, right?
这里的人全都有杀害树里小姐的动机 不是吗
What are you talking about?
你在说什么
You're the make-up artist Natsuki-san Sakai, right?
你是化妆师酒井夏树小姐吧
Can you explain it?
到底是怎么回事
I've been with Juri-san for the longest time.
我和树里小姐在一起的时间最长
So I believe I'm the one most familiar with her relationships with others.
所以应该很了解她周围的人际关系了
First of all, Ban-san.
首先是伴先生
He is the stage manager in this play,
他虽然兼任了这次演出的舞台监督
but in fact, it had been our chairman Juri-san doing all this job.
但实际上平时一直是剧团团长树里小姐在做这件事
Originally, he was the one who trained Juri-san to become an actress.
原本树里小姐是他一手培养成演员的
But now, it all reversed.
可是现在正好相反
He didn't even dare to oppose Juri-san.
他不敢对树里小姐有丝毫的违抗
I've seen him getting reprimanded by his wife Tenko-san for this matter several times.
我看到过好几次他因此被妻子天子责备
Narusawa-san agreed to divorce Juri-san three years ago.
成泽先生在三年前答应了树里小姐的协议离婚
But it seems he still has feelings for her now.
可是似乎现在仍对她有依恋
No matter how many times he begged her for reconciliation, he was rejected.
几次提出复婚却被拒绝了
Juri-san seems to be getting tired of her young lover, Shinjo-san.
树里小姐似乎也厌倦了年轻的恋人新庄先生
She even asked me to introduce her to someone cuter.
要我介绍有没有更可爱一点的人
Then there is her manager, Masayo-san.
然后是经纪人真佐代小姐
Juri-san always criticized her as dull and not smart enough,
总是被树里小姐说她阴沉不够伶俐
and always insulted her in front of everyone.
常在大家面前羞辱她
And myself. I was always being abused by Juri-san, who was very selfish.
各位 我也总是被任性的树里小姐呼来唤去
I wanted to change jobs, but she interfered me every time.
虽然想换其他的工作却总被她阻挠
I was happy that she liked me, but I also resented her.
虽然受到器重很开心却也很恨她
Right? It's wouldn't be surprising if any one of us wanted to kill her.
对吧 大家要杀害她也不是什么出人意料的事
Wait, Genta-kun.
等一下 元太
How can you eat at a time like this?
在这种时候你还真能吃得下呀
It's a shame to waste it.
剩下来太可惜了嘛
Yummy.
好吃
If there was poison on her fingers...
如果手指上沾了毒的话
Shinjo-san was the first one who touched Juri-san's hand.
最初碰过树里小姐手的是新庄先生
Could it be that he poisoned it at that time?
莫非是那个时候下的毒
No.
不是
There were other possibilities.
还有其他可能
What if the poison was on that signature pen?
如果那支签名笔涂有毒的话
Maybe the poison was on the switch for the reading light.
也可能那时候在阅读灯的开关上下毒
Or perhaps, the poison was placed on areas in the lavatory
还是在厕所内树里小姐可能触及的地方涂上毒
That's right, after Juri-san went into the lavatory, she came out very quickly.
这么说来树里小姐进厕所后很快就出来了
Wait a minute.
等一下
Before that...
在这之前…
I see.
是这样啊
So that's what happened.
原来是这样
That's why at that time...
所以那个时候才…
I'm not feeling very well.
总觉得身体不舒服
I've figured out this trick,
我明白了 这个手法
and the culprit who did it!
还有实施这个手法的犯人
Hey, Uncle Mouri!
咦 叔叔
What's that?
那个是什么
What is it?
什么啊
There's nothing there.
什么都没有啊
What?
什么
Okay, right now.
好 就是现在
Oh no!
糟了
What is it?
什么东西啊
I thought there was something.
是我看错了
I gotta go to the toilet!
去厕所一下
What's wrong with this kid?
搞什么鬼啊 这小子
No choice.
没办法
Although this will be the first time...
虽然是第一次
You...
你啊
Stop putting on airs.
就不要再装模作样了
Oh no, I made a mistake.
糟糕 弄错了
Sonoko?
园子
Me?
我
That's enough.
到此为止吧
It's about time to tell the truth.
差不多该说出真相了
What?
什么
Forget it.
算了
It's not like this case is of a caliber that requires "Sleeping Kogoro" to solve it.
这件案子不值得我们"沉睡的小五郎"出场
Okay, then I'll tell the truth.
好吧 就由我来说出真相吧
No way.
不是吧
Great!
好棒
It's Auntie's show of deduction today!
今天是伯母的推理秀啊
Let's begin with the method the culprit used to let Juri-san touch the poison.
首先是犯人如何让树里小姐沾上毒药的
That was not some great trick.
那并不是什么了不起的手法
I'll talk about it now.
现在就来说一下
Right.
是的
It was ear clearing.
就是耳压平衡
Ear clearing?
耳压平衡
The culprit knew that Juri-san would definitely clear her ears
犯人知道树里小姐上了飞机一定会做耳压平衡
That is, using her thumb and forefinger to pinch her nose and blow.
就是用大拇指和食指捏住鼻子吐气这个办法
And the culprit knew she would use her right hand.
而且还一直用的是右手
Perhaps some of you know that
应该有人知道
this method of ear clearing is among the first things taught to new divers.
在潜水时最先学习的就是这个耳压平衡
The advanced diver might be able to clear ears without pinching nose,
熟练以后不用捏鼻子也可以做到
but Juri-san was just a beginner.
树里小姐还只不过刚开始学潜水
Nine times out of ten, she would have done it.
十有八九会这样做的
Is that right, dear?
是这样吧 老公
Wait.
等等
Why would you know this?
为什么你会知道这些
This method of ear clearing is just like how Ayumi-chan just felt.
这个耳压平衡就像刚才步美做的一样
It's kind of embarrassing for a female to do in front of someone of the opposite gender.
是女性在异性面前不太好意思做的动作
Besides, Juri-san was an actress.
而且树里小姐身为女演员
And you were sitting next to her.
旁边坐着的是你
Although you're just a fool, you're still of the opposite gender.
就算是个傻瓜 但也总是异性
Fool?
傻瓜
That was why Juri-san
所以树里小姐
went to the bathroom to clear her ears in private.
为了避开你做耳压平衡而去了洗手间
Then she returned to her seat,
然后回到座位
picked up the chocolate with her right thumb and forefinger,
用捏过鼻子的右手大拇指和食指拿起巧克力吃了
And then, she licked the cocoa powder off her hand as usual.
接着像往常一样舔掉手上的可可粉
It was because of this habit,
正是因为这个习惯
the poison entered her body without she knowing it.
使得毒药完全进入了体内却浑然不知
What do you mean?
到底怎么回事
Where exactly was the poison?
毒药到底在哪里
It's kind of hard to breathe, isn't it?
好像有点喘不上气来
Strange.
真奇怪
Actually, the poison had already slowly entered Juri-san's body.
其实毒药在此之前就已经慢慢渗入树里小姐体内了
So
没错
the reason why she wasn't feeling well
她之所以会感到不舒服
was because the poison was being absorbed through her skin.
就是因为毒药通过皮肤渗入体内的关系
Skin?
皮肤
If so, could it be...
那样的话 难道…
Right.
是的
Inside the car in the parking lot at Haneda Airport,
在羽田机场停车场的车里
the culprit who applied the poisoned foundation
把混有毒药的粉底涂在树里小姐鼻子的两侧
to both sides of Juri-san's nose to kill Juri-san
将树里小姐置于死地的犯人
was Natsuki-san Sakai.
是酒井夏树小姐
It was you.
就是你
That's impossible.
不可能的
Although it was an interesting deduction.
虽然推理很有趣
Conan-kun told me
我听柯南说了
that you once scolded the kids who played with the foundation.
你曾经训斥过拿粉底玩的孩子们
It was the day you committed the murder.
在下毒杀人的当天
Although these kids were just playing with it,
虽然孩子只是玩玩
as a precaution against the possibility of their touching it,
但为了以防万一不让她们碰到
you still hid the foundation properly, right?
你还是把粉底妥善藏了起来
Then, show me the evidence!
那么就拿出证据来看看呀
Indeed.
不错
If we could find poison and foundation mixture
如果在树里小姐的大拇指和食指上验出
on Juri-san's thumb and forefinger,
毒药和粉底混杂在一起的话
it would have served as an evidence.
的确可以作为证据
But given that Juri-san licked her fingers,
但因为树里小姐舔了手指
this evidence has disappeared.
这个证据也就消失了
But there is other evidence.
但是还有其他的证据
The poisoned foundation and the sponge.
含有毒药的粉底盒及海绵
Smart as you are, you wouldn't have brought them aboard.
那么聪明的你当然不会把它们带上飞机
It would also be dangerous if you threw them in the airport trash cans.
但把它们扔在机场的垃圾筒里也很危险
So if it were me, I would have sent them out,
所以如果是我的话就会寄出去的
addressed back to my own home,
邮寄到自己家里
via the mail.
寄邮包
If we contact the post office at the airport
如果联系机场的邮局
and check her mail parcel, we'll know.
检查一下邮寄物品就知道了
Okay, can you tell us now?
好了 可以告诉我们了吗
Your own house address.
你自己家的地址
That woman destroyed my dream.
那个女人摧毁了我的梦想
Dream?
梦想
I've always dreamed
我一直都梦想
to become a great make-up artist in Hollywood.
可以在好莱坞用我的化妆技术干出一番事业
To fulfill my dream,
为了实现那个梦想
I studied abroad at a makeup school in Los Angeles
到洛杉矶的化妆学校留学
and learned to speak conversational English.
还学了一口流利的英语
Upon my return to Japan,
接着回国后
while doing makeup for that woman,
一边替那个女人化妆
I continued to write letters to Hollywood seeking employment.
一边继续写信到好莱坞求职
Then, one month ago,
后来在一个月前
a Hollywood actress came to Japan.
好莱坞女明星来日本的时候
She recognized my make-up skill and aesthetic intelligence.
肯定了我的化妆技术和审美能力
Her agent asked me if I wanted to work with her.
通过代理人来问我要不要一起工作
To me,
对我来说
it was a once-in-a-lifetime chance.
这是一生一次的机会
But...
但是
But that woman intervened and destroyed this chance in secret!
但是那个女人却暗中横加干涉破坏了这个机会
Maybe she really liked you and didn't want you to go.
也许她真的舍不得你
If she really needed me because of my make-up skills,
如果我的化妆对她来说是不可缺少的
then I could have forgiven her!
那我还可以原谅她
But it was not like that.
但不是这样的
That woman just used me as a servant to her whims.
那个女人只是把我当作一个跟班方便她呼来唤去而已
After knowing this,
明白这件事之后
I realized I had no choice but to do this.
我想我只有动手了
That woman had destroyed my pride as a make-up artist.
那个女人毁了我作为化妆师的尊严
Your pride as a make-up artist?
作为化妆师的尊严吗
Don't be ridiculous.
不要说笑了
Then why would you use makeup as a murder weapon?
那为什么要用化妆品来作为杀人的凶器呢
At this moment,
现在的你
you are not qualified to talk about pride!
没有资格说什么尊严
I...
我…
You are still young.
你还很年轻
You can start over after you've repaid your debt.
赎完罪后再重新开始吧
What's going on?
怎么回事
What's this feeling of dread?
这种不祥的感觉
The nerves in my head are tingling.
脑袋里的神经在隐隐作痛
No!
糟了
The snacks you just gave them!
刚才送给机长们的点心
Tell them not to eat those snacks!
让他们不要吃
If you don't hurry,
不快点的话
the captains will be in danger!
机长他们就危险了
Are you stupid?
你是笨蛋啊
There's no poison in the snacks.
毒药又没有渗入点心
I didn't mean snacks!
不是点心
The captains' fingers might have gotten poison on them!
机长们的手指上说不定已经沾上了毒药
What?
什么
What's going on?
到底怎么回事
Tell me what's going on!
快说清楚
Yes, I'll be right there.
知道了 马上来
Sorry for the intrusion.
打扰了
As expected.
果然
Captain!
机长
Captain, what happened?
机长 怎么了
Are you all right?
不要紧吧
What's going on?
怎么回事
Nakaya-san!
中屋先生
Are you all right?
不要紧吧
Captain!
机长
No!
糟了
The auto-pilot mode has been disengaged!
自动驾驶模式解除了
Captain, pull yourself together!
机长 振作一点
Captain!
机长
Get him up!
快拉他起来
Move the seat out of the way!
把座位往后拉
Captain!
机长
All right, the auto-pilot switch is...
好 自动驾驶按钮是…
Shinjo-san.
新庄先生
Good job, kid.
干得不错 小弟弟
Everything is all right now.
已经没事了
Get a doctor over here right away!
马上找医生过来
Got it.
知道了
We're currently having a medical emergency on board.
现在机内有紧急病人
If there's a doctor on board, please contact to the nearest flight attendant.
如果乘客中有医生的话请联系附近的乘务员
Indeed, they've been poisoned by a fast-acting poison.
果然是急性中毒
I will administer first-aid now.
我会帮他们进行急救
Please move them into the passenger cabin.
请将他们移到客舱
Okay.
好的
Narusawa-san! Ban-san!
成泽先生 伴先生
Please give us a hand!
麻烦过来帮一下忙
Okay.
是
Get the medical kit!
去拿急救箱
Conan-kun, why would the captains also get poisoned?
柯南 为什么机长他们也会中毒呢
Just now, Juri-san went to the cockpit.
刚才树里小姐到驾驶舱去过
At that time, the captain and co-pilot kissed Juri-san's hand.
那时机长和副驾驶吻了树里小姐的手
Oh, I see.
原来如此
So they touched the poison on her hand.
所以碰到沾在她手上的毒药
How unlucky.
真不走运
If it was just a normal handshake,
如果只是平常的握手
the poison would have only gotten on their palms,
毒药只会沾到他们的手掌
but wouldn't have gotten into their mouths.
不会进入口中
How is it going, doctor?
怎么样 医生
Fortunately, they only ingested a small amount of poison.
幸亏只摄入了微量的毒药
Their lives are not in danger.
没有生命危险
But they're both too unconscious to operate the plane.
但是他们现在意识模糊根本无法驾驶飞机
What?
什么
The captain and the co-pilot are unconscious?
机长和副驾驶意识不清
Excuse me, could I have your name?
对不起 您的名字是…
I'm a passenger, Shinjo.
乘客新庄
Shinjo-san.
新庄先生
Do you know the current flight situation?
你知道飞机现在的飞行状况吗
The current altitude is 12,000 feet. Current speed is 280 knots.
现在高度12000英尺 速度280节
Fortunately, the ILS for landing has already been inputted.
所幸自动操纵系统连降落指令都已经被输入了
I have some experience operating the flaps and landing gears,
襟翼和起落架的操作我有经验所以懂点皮毛
Now I need instructions with regards to the timing.
剩下的只要给我操作时间上的指示
Got it.
明白了
We have cleared all other landings and takeoffs,
其他飞机起降已全部停止
and put in immediate requests for other captains to stand by at the tower.
还紧急联络了其他机长到塔台待命
The current weather around Hakodate is unstable.
现在因为函馆上空的天气不稳定
All incoming and outbound flights have been suspended.
所有出发及到达的航班起降都已停止
We appreciate your patience during this period.
请各位乘客稍候片刻
Ladies and gentlemen.
女士们先生们
So...
所以呢
I'll take over the captain's seat.
我坐机长的位置
As for the co-pilot's seat...
副驾驶的位置的话
That's right, you'll take that seat, okay?
对了 就你来坐吧
You did a great job pulling up that control yoke just now.
刚才拉起操作杆干得非常不错
I've done it many times in the arcade center!
我在游戏中心操纵过很多次了
Conan-kun! It's unfair!
柯南好狡猾
I want to sit there too!
我也要坐
Me too!
我也是
This is not a game.
这可不是玩
In addition, there is no need to operate now.
另外现在也不需要什么操作
Just during the landing,
只是在着陆的时候
I may need to do a few things to operate.
需要稍微操作一下
That's why I asked him to assist.
所以才让他帮忙
Even so,
就算是这样
why such a little kid?
为什么让这么小的孩子
Just leave it to me.
总之就交给我吧
All right, we'll be landing in 15 minutes.
好了 再有15分钟就要着陆了
Please return to the passenger cabin, everyone.
各位请回到机舱吧
Shinjo said he had some experience in this field.
新庄说他自己有这方面的经验
Maybe he has a license to fly some small plane like a Cessna.
也许有赛斯纳(Cessna)这类小型飞机的驾照吧
Dad, Mom seems to be asleep.
爸爸 妈妈好像睡着了
What?
什么
Everyone, please hurry back to your seats and fasten your seat belts tightly immediately.
各位请立刻回到座位上并系好安全带
Dad.
爸爸
Just sit next to Mom, okay?
你就坐在妈妈的旁边吧
Geez!
真是的
Fine, I guess I have no choice.
没办法
Hey, wake up!
喂 醒醒啊
Hey!
喂
What the...
真是
You're Kiddo, right?
你是基德吧
What did you say?
你说什么
Stop playing dumb, asshole.
混蛋 别装糊涂了
How could there be any normal human being
这世上哪里会有让小学生坐驾驶座的人啊
So I'm exposed.
还是暴露了
Now the real Shinjo...
现在真正的新庄
He's dressed up as Kiddo at Juri-san's villa in Hakodate.
假扮成基德在树里小姐函馆的别墅
Right?
对不对
When you appeared,
你出现的时候
Juri-san was not very happy.
树里小姐很不高兴啊
I guess she told Shinjo to be a fake Kiddo
作为晚会的余兴节目
as entertainment for the party, right?
才让新庄假扮基德的吧
You're really great!
真了不起
But there's another person who thought Kiddo wouldn't give up just like that,
不过 还有一个认为基德不会就此罢手的人
and also went to Hakodate.
也去了函馆
He's probably chasing after the fake Kiddo right now.
现在说不定正在和假基德玩警察抓小偷呢
By the way, when are you planning to take the Jewel of Destiny?
对了 你打算什么时候取走命运宝石呢
I don't want it anymore.
我不要了
You should know about it, right?
你也知道吧
The real star sapphire is supposed to be cold when it touches your mouth.
真正的星蓝宝石含在嘴里应该是冰凉的
That's a fake.
那个是赝品
So you did that just to ascertain it.
那么做原来是为了确认这件事
I guess it was to attract playgoers to see "Josephine"
恐怕是为了吸引《约瑟芬》的观众
that they publicized that fake as the real one.
才拿赝品来冒充真品
What are you gonna do?
怎么样
Arrest me?
要抓我吗
Great Detective?
大侦探
Of course.
当然
After this giant mental bird returns to its nest.
等这只巨大的铁鸟回巢以后再说
Flight SKJ865.
SKJ865班机
The Hakodate Tower is now taking over.
现在开始由函馆塔台接管
Please change the frequency to 118.35.
请将频率调整为118.35
118.35, got it.
118.35 明白
This is Hakodate Tower. I'm the control chief, Uesugi.
这里是函馆塔台管制部长上杉
Captain Shimaoka will be in charge now.
接下来由机长岛冈指挥
This is Shimaoka.
我是岛冈
Can you see the MCP, mode control panel?
有没有看到MCP模式控制面板
Yes, I saw it.
是的 看到了
Then please press the APP button on that.
那么请按下上面的APP按钮
Then the plane will automatically lower itself onto the runway.
这样飞机就会自动降落在跑道上
Understood.
明白
APP.
APP
That one.
是那个
Pressed!
按下了
Who are you?
你是谁
I'm Conan Edogawa.
我是江户川柯南
Shinjo-san's assistant.
新庄先生的助手
Assistant? Is there a child sitting next to you?
助手 你旁边坐着个孩子吗
Kid, don't touch the control yoke or any of the other switches!
孩子 绝对不能碰操作杆和其他的开关
Understand?
知道吗
We can relax for now.
这样就暂时放心了
Do you know how to operate the flaps and landing gear?
你知道怎么操作襟翼和起落架吗
I do.
知道
My dad taught me how to fly a Cessna in Hawaii.
爸爸在夏威夷教过我开赛斯纳小型飞机
I see.
这样啊
I knew I chose the right person.
果然没有选错人
But I just learned the theory about it.
不过那只是纸上谈兵
I've never actually flown one.
没有实际起飞过
This weather is horrible.
天气很糟啊
But I think they'll be able to land. Right?
不过应该能着陆吧
Heavy rain, huh?
雨好大啊
The wind is pretty strong too.
风也刮得很猛
Don't fall, plane!
不要掉下去啊飞机
It's the airport.
是机场
Here it comes.
来了
Flight 865.
865班机
Flaps to 1.
襟翼调整到1
Flaps to 5.
襟翼调整到5
Flaps to 10.
襟翼调整到10
Lower the landing gears. Flaps to 20.
放下起落架 襟翼调整到20
It's finally time to land.
终于要开始着陆了
What was that?
什么
It was the lightning.
是闪电
The plane has been struck by lightning.
飞机被闪电击中了
This is Flight 865
这里是865班机
The plane was struck by lightning and all the displays have turned off!
飞机被闪电击中画面全部消失了
Calm down. Turn the white knob next to the instrument panel.
冷静 转动仪表板边的白钮
They're on.
亮了
Not yet.
还没
The auto-pilot light is not on!
自动驾驶灯没有亮
What?
什么
Abort the landing!
暂停着陆
Pull up on the control yoke as hard as you can!
用最大的力气拉起操纵杆
All right. Retract the landing gears.
好 收起起落架
Done.
收起来了
Good, just keep climbing up.
好 就这样继续上升
No, the wind is blowing it off course!
不好 被风卷走了
Turn right! Turn right!
往右转 turn right
It'll hit the terminal building!
会撞到候机大楼的
Bring up the nose!
拉起机头
Oh...no.
不…不好
Awesome!
厉害
Are the airport and the cathetometer okay?
机场和高差计没事吧
Flight 865, can you hear me?
865班机 听得见吗
Yes, I can hear you.
听得见
What's the status of the damage?
损害状况如何
No injuries in the tower.
塔内人员都安然无恙
But I'm afraid the runway can't be used for now.
不过跑道恐怕无法马上使用
How is it going with your side?
你那边怎么样
We've lost Engine Number 2.
2号引擎脱落
It's okay.
没关系
The remaining three will be sufficient to make a landing.
剩下的三个着陆足够了
How about the balance?
另外 平衡呢
Balance is fine.
平衡没问题
We've adjusted the rudder and cut the throttle down to position three.
现在将方向舵调整为第3节流阀
Good, tell me your current altitude and speed.
好 现在的高度和速度是
3,000 feet and 200 knots.
3000英尺和200节
Adjust the flaps to 5.
将襟翼调整到5
Level out.
变为水平飞行
Turn the nose to 180 degrees.
机首朝180度方向
Ascend to 4500 feet.
上升到4500英尺
Got it.
明白
So now we gotta circle around and wait for the order, right?
接下来就是盘旋待命吗
As long as the auto-pilot function is back,
只要自动驾驶仪能恢复
and the runway is restored to its original state,
跑道清除完毕恢复原状后
we'll be able to use the ILS to land again.
就能用RLS再次进行自动降落
Idiot! Didn't I tell you there aren't enough fire trucks?
笨蛋 不是说了消防车不够吗
Put out the fire on the runway!
快熄灭跑道上的火
Conan-kun, it's not good!
柯南 不好了 不好了
One of the engines fell off!
有一个引擎掉了
I know that, don't worry about it.
这我知道了 你们不用担心
The remaining three engines is enough to make a landing.
用剩下的三个引擎就足以降落了
And there's plenty of fuel...
而且燃料也很充足
What's wrong?
怎么了
There's not much fuel left.
燃料已经所剩无几了
What?
什么
Not much fuel?
没有燃料了
We're out of fuel?
燃料没了吗
What's going on?
这是怎么回事啊
Is it because the engine fell off?
难道是引擎脱落的关系吗
No.
不
Generally, all four engines are supplied by different fuel tanks.
一般四个引擎都是由不同的燃料箱供应燃料的
The fuel valve is open.
燃料阀打开着
What's that thing called the fuel something?
那个叫燃什么的是什么东西啊
It's the fuel valve.
是燃料阀
If that switch is pressed,
按下那个开关
those valves that separate the fuel tanks will be opened,
隔开各个燃料箱的阀门就会被打开
making it all one big fuel tank.
就成为一个大的燃料箱了
Damn, how could this happen?
可恶 怎么会这样
It's all that old geezer's fault.
都是那个臭老头
We can't delay any longer.
现在一刻也不能耽误了
Yeah.
是啊
There should be a map over there.
那边应该有地图
-Hakodate Tower. -There should be a map over there.
呼叫塔台
-This is Flight 865.
这里是865号班机 那边应该有地图
-Someone bring it here.
帮我拿一下 这里是865号班机
Mayday!
突发紧急事件
Hakodate Tower! Please respond!
塔台听到请回答
Flight 865...
865号班机
This is Hakodate Tower. I can't hear you clearly. Please speak louder.
这里是塔台 听不清楚 请说大声点
It's too noisy. I can't hear you clearly.
噪音太大 听不清啊
What's going on exactly?
到底发生什么事了
Professor!
博士
We lost an engine.
掉了个引擎
And the fuel is running out!
连燃料好像也要没了
What did you say?
你说什么
Map, map, map...
地图 地图 地图
That red one, right?
就是那本红色的吧
Found it.
找到了
Damn it!
可恶
The auto-pilot, the runway, the fuel...
自动驾驶系统 跑道 再是燃料
Now even the radio is gone too!
就连无线电也失灵了
Are you saying the auto-pilot system is gone?
你说自动驾驶系统失灵
So, are you piloting manually right now?
也就是说 现在是你在手动驾驶吗
Conan-kun, here's the map.
柯南 地图给你
Thank you.
谢了
There's about 3,000 pounds of fuel left.
燃料大约还剩下3000磅
If it needs 300 pounds per minute,
每分钟需要300磅的话
we can only have 10 minutes of flight time left.
我们只能飞行10分钟了
We must find somewhere to land within that time.
一定要在这段时间里找到某个可以降落的地点
What do you mean by "somewhere"?
某个是什么意思
It is impossible to recover the runway in 10 minutes.
跑道是不可能在10分钟内恢复了
Chitose? How about the New Chitose Airport?
去千岁 去新千岁机场呢
It's a bit risky.
有些冒险
We'll probably run out of fuel before we get there.
燃料很可能在途中就耗尽了
What about other airports?
那其它的机场呢
Aren't there any other airports around here?
这附近没有别的机场了吗
There aren't.
没有
There might be an agricultural takeoff and landing strip or a Self Defense Force base.
可能会有农场的起降场或是自卫队基地
But the length of the runway is not long enough.
不过跑道的长度都不够
Then how about we try to land on the road instead?
那干脆就在公路上降落如何
Hokkaido has many wide and straight roads.
北海道有许多既宽又笔直的大道
It's not possible.
不可能的
The span between the wheels on this plane is 11 meters.
这架飞机两轮间距11米
All roads spanning 12 or more meters across
宽度12米以上的道路
are required to have a central divider as well as traffic signboards.
路中央必定设有隔离带和标识牌
And there would likely be houses and power lines around.
而且周围还有民宅与电线杆
How about a ranch?
那么牧场呢
No way.
不行
The ground would be too soft.
地面太松软了
It would be better to try a water landing in the sea nearby.
还不如就在附近的海域降落
No, the waves would overturn the plane.
不行 海浪反而会使机体翻覆
Where is it? Where is it?
在哪里 在哪里
There must be somewhere we can land.
应该有能够降落的地方
Somewhere long, straight and clear.
需要又长又直而且周围又空旷的地方啊
What will happen if we can't land?
那个 如果不能降落的话我们会怎么样
If so...
那样的话
the plane would crash, right?
飞机一定会坠毁吧
But I don't want to die yet.
可我还不想死呢
Conan-kun, I know a place.
柯南 我知道哪里有了
A place that is long, straight and clear!
又长又直 而且周围空旷的地方
It was showed on TV last time when we were watching dolphins and whales.
上回电视里播放观赏海豚鲸鱼时有拍摄到的
When we were watching dolphins and whales?
观赏海豚鲸鱼的话
Was it Murolan?
是室兰吗
The piers!
码头
Nippon Steel Pier.
新日铁码头
Nakau Pier.
中卯码头
Motowanishi Pier
本轮西码头
Muroran Pier.
室兰码头
Nisseki Pier.
日石码头
Found it.
找到了
Sakimori Pier!
崎守码头
The length is about 1400 meters, and the width is about 30 meters.
长度大约1400米宽度大约也有30米吧
But the width of this plane is...
但这架飞机的宽度呢
About 60 meters.
60米左右
But if we can let one side of the wings hover over the sea, maybe...
但如果让一侧的机翼伸出海面的话也许…
Not possible.
行不通
The distance is not long enough.
距离不够长
The stopping distance of this plane should be more than 2000 meters.
这种飞机降落时的滑行距应该会超过2000米
And there is the problem with the integrity of the ground surface.
而且还有地面强度的问题
I don't know if it's lucky or unlucky,
不知是幸运呢还是不幸
there is not much fuel left,
燃料所剩无几
and there are not many passengers.
乘客也不多
The lighter the weight, the shorter the stopping distance will be.
重量越是轻滑行的距离也就会相对缩短
If the wind direction is good, it may be even shorter.
如果风向配合的话可能会再缩短些
I remember the weather report at Haneda said
我记得在羽田看到的天气预报说
there will be strong winds from the west throughout the night!
今天整晚会有强烈的西风
Are you sure, Mitsuhiko?
光彦 是真的吗
Yes!
是的
This pier stretches east to west.
这个码头是东西向的
If we land from the east against the west wind,
只要顶着西风从东边降落的话
we may be able to land safely.
也许能够顺利地降落呢
No way!
不可能
When we collided with the control tower,
刚才撞到塔台时
my left hand was badly injured.
我左手受到重创
I've been piloting the plane with my right hand alone.
现在光靠着右手在操纵飞机
If we land manually,
如果使用手动降落的话
I'll have to hold the control yoke with both hands.
必须用双手握住操纵杆才行
How is your vision?
你的视力如何
1.5 in both eyes.
两眼都是1.5
Do you have any disease?
有什么疾病吗
No.
没有
Your bust, waist and hip sizes?
胸围腰围和臀围呢
Well, my bust is...
那个 胸围是…
What?
什么啊
Good answer. You're passed.
答得很好 合格了
Sit here instead of me.
你就代替我坐在这里吧
What are you talking about?
你在说什么啊
How can you let me fly a plane?
竟然要我开飞机
Don't be nervous, I'll teach you how to operate it behind you.
放心吧 我会在后面教你操作的
All you have to do is to hold the control yoke tightly.
你只要握紧操纵杆就行了
No, I can't do that!
不行 绝对办不到的
The plane!
飞机
The plane is falling down!
飞机正在下降啊
It's going to crash!
要掉下去了啊
Ran-nee-chan, sit down quickly!
小兰姐姐 快点坐下
Now, slowly pull up the control yoke.
然后慢慢地拉起操纵杆
Calm down.
冷静一点
Good job!
不错 干得漂亮
Easy, huh?
很简单吧
What?
什么啊
What direction to Muroran?
室兰的方向在哪里
I'm looking for it.
我正在找
Found it.
找到了
The flight path from Hakodate to Sapporo happens to pass near Muroran.
函馆飞住札晃的航道刚好通过室兰附近
The bearing is 023 degrees.
方向是023度
023, right?
023是吧
We'll pass over a mountain.
要越过山
The altitude must be more than 5,000 feet.
高度要在5000英尺以上
Understood.
了解
Excuse me.
麻烦一下
Please tell the passengers that we are flying to Chitose.
请告诉乘客们我们正飞住千岁
Yes, sir.
好的
Besides, please transfer all the first-class passengers on the second floor downstairs.
顺便请二层头等舱的乘客全坐到下面去
If they find out that a high school girl is flying the plane,
要是让他们知道是高中女生在开飞机的话
they will panic.
大家一定要惊慌失措的吧
You guys should go back to the cabin too.
你们几个也回机舱去吧
There's nothing else you can do here.
在这里你们也帮不了什么忙
I'd like for you to calm the other kids down.
我倒是希望你们去安抚一下其它的孩子
This is very important.
这可是非常重要的任务哦
If you can't do it, I'll ask someone else.
办不到的话 我可要拜托别人了
How about it? Can you do it?
怎么样 你们能办到吗
Understood.
我们明白了
We'll try.
我们试试看
We'll take care of it!
全包在我们身上了
Very well. Then I'm counting on you.
很好 那就拜托你们了
Yes, sir!
遵命
I'm staying here.
我要留在这里
If anything happens...
万一出了什么事
I'm the only one who can help Ran.
也只有我能帮助小兰了
Okay, then.
那好吧
I'll come back later to explain the other controls en route.
我过会儿再来说明其他的装置
There's not much time left.
现在没时间了
Let's go.
走吧
Flight SKJ865.
SKJ865班机
This is Hakodate Tower.
这里是函馆塔台
Do you copy?
听到没有
Please respond!
听到请回答
It's no use.
没办法了
They're not even responding on the emergency line.
连紧急线路也没反应
Look!
你快看
Flight 865 is flying away.
865班机要飞走了
Where are they going?
他们想开到哪里去啊
That's the Great Shiratori Bridge, right?
那座就是白鸟大桥啊
It's quite impressive.
造得还真不错呢
Isn't it, Shiratori-kun?
是吧 白鸟
No, Inspector.
错了 警官
It should be the Hakucho Bridge.
应该是天鹅大桥才对
Coming to Muroran as you proposed on the way
你提议趁去札晃出差的回程
back from our business trip to Sapporo was well worth it.
顺道来室兰看看还真是不错呢
The Great Shiratori Bridge is so beautiful.
白鸟大桥真是好美啊
I wish I could come here with Miwako-san one day.
真希望有一天能和美和子一起来这里啊
This is definitely not on my list.
这可绝对不行
There are so many patrol cars.
好多警车啊
They're probably chasing after a vicious criminal.
可能是在追捕穷凶极恶的歹徒吧
Well, let's take a look.
那好 我们也过去瞧瞧吧
Attention, all passengers.
各位乘客请注意
I'm scared.
好害怕
-There has been a small accident on the plane. -I'm scared.
本机遇上一些小意外
-We'll be fine, right? -There has been a small accident on the plane.
没事的吧
-We are currently heading to New Chitose Airport. -We'll be fine, right?
目前正飞往备用的新千岁机场
The flight is normal.
航行一切正常
We are sorry for the inconvenience.
给各位带来不便
-We're actually going to Muroran, right? -We are sorry for the inconvenience,
其实是要去室兰才对吧
-and thank you for your understanding. -We're actually going to Muroran, right?
我们深感抱歉
We're approaching Muroran.
室兰就要到了
Lower the altitude to 2,000 feet.
把高度降到2000英尺
All right.
好的
I see it! There's a light!
看到了 有灯光
It's Muroran Port!
是室兰港
Sakimori Pier is more to the left!
再左边一点就是崎守码头了
It's on the other side of the Hakucho Bridge.
在天鹅大桥的另一端
It's bad!
糟糕
It's so dark ahead. I can't see anything.
前面好暗我什么都看不清
Hey, do we really have to land here?
喂 真的要在这里降落吗
What now?
该怎么办呢
There's no turning back.
已经无法回头了
Is there really no problem, Conan-kun?
真的没有问题吗 柯南
What do you want?
你想干什么
Looks like it's not good. I'm bailing.
看来形势不妙 我就先下去了
Good luck.
Good Luck
Wait!
等等
Hey, don't go!
喂 别走
Ran-nee-chan, lower the nose!
小兰姐姐 机首向下
Wait, what are you doing, exactly?
等等 你到底想干嘛啊
Grab onto something!
找点东西抓牢了
What? What's going on?
什么 怎么回事啊
It's okay. Don't worry.
没事 不用担心
Hold the plane steady.
先稳住机身
Kai... Kai...
怪…怪…
Kaitou Kid!
怪盗基德
See you later, young lady.
后会有期了 小姐
I hope we'll meet again under the bright moonlight next time.
希望下回我们能在皎洁的月光下重逢
Okay.
好的
Bye.
失陪了
He jumped off?
他跳下去了
Right, Shinjo-san was Kiddo.
没错 新庄先生原来就是基德
I see. That's why he pressed the depressurization button.
是吗 所以他会按下降舱压的按钮
He must have been afraid that the plane would crash, so he fled.
一定是怕飞机坠毁所以先溜了
I used to admire him that much! It turns out that he's just a coward.
亏我还这么崇拜他 真是太差劲了
Sonoko-nee-chan, it's a little early to say that the plane is gonna crash, isn't it?
园子姐姐 现在说坠机还早了点吧
But Conan-kun.
可是 柯南
What should we do now?
接下来该怎么办呢
Now it's up to us to land the plane, Ran-nee-chan.
如今只好靠我们自己来降落了 小兰姐姐
Don't worry, Ran.
放心好了 小兰
They always say that the wisdom of three fools catches up with one pearl, right?
不是常说 三个臭皮匠抵过一个珍珠亮吗
Believe me, we'll find a way!
一定会有办法的
Come on, the saying goes...
拜托 那句话应该是
The saying goes, the wisdom of three fools catches up with one wise man.
那句话应该是抵过一个诸葛亮才对吧
Was I wrong?
是我说错了吗
Anyway, let's circle around the pier and see the situation.
我们先在码头上方转两圈看看情况吧
Help!
救命啊
Help me!
快救救我
I'm not Kiddo! You've got the wrong person!
我不是基德啊 你们认错人了
Then why were you running away?
那你为什么要逃跑
Because I stole a clock.
因为我偷了个表
That's right, then you must be Kiddo!
那就对了 还敢说你不是基德
Inspector Nakamori!
中森警官
What?
干嘛
What's that?
那是什么
Isn't it obvious? It's Kiddo.
那还用问 是基德啊
Kiddo?
基德
Then who are you?
那你是谁
I told you you've got the wrong person.
我都说是你们认错人了
Sonoko-nee-chan, what's the situation?
园子姐姐 情况如何
Not good at all.
完全不行
There are some places with lights,
虽然有些地方有灯光
but most of the place is pitch-black and I can't see anything.
但大部分地方全是黑乎乎的 什么也看不清
Damn it!
可恶
Ran-nee-chan, are you all right?
小兰姐姐 你还好吧
Ran, what's wrong?
小兰 你怎么了
I don't know, I suddenly feel...
我也不清楚 忽然觉得身体…
Conan-kun.
柯南
I can't do it after all.
果然我还是做不到
No way.
不会的
You can do it, Ran-nee-chan!
你一定可以的 小兰姐姐
Not good. It's too dangerous with her like this.
糟糕 这样下去太危险了
Sonoko-nee-chan, switch me for a moment.
园子姐姐 替我一下
I need to go to the toilet.
我要上厕所
Toilet?
厕所
I'll be right back.
马上就回来
In case the radio comes back on,
无线电可能会接通
put on your headsets!
你们要戴上耳机哦
Wait a minute.
等等
Geez, how can you go to the toilet at a time like this?
真是的 这种非常时刻竟然上什么厕所
That's why I dislike that little brat.
所以我才讨厌小鬼嘛
Hello?
喂喂 喂喂
Ran!
小兰
Can you hear me, Ran?
听得到吗 小兰
Shinichi?
新一
I'm calling from the control tower in Sapporo.
我现在是从札晃的塔台打来的
It seems that you are in danger now.
你们现在的处境好像很危险
But it will be okay.
不过已经没事了
As long as you follow my instructions, you'll land safely.
你冷静地照我的话去做就一定能安全降落的
I will protect you. Don't worry.
我一定会保护你的 不用担心
Ran, are you there?
小兰 你在听吗
Ran, answer him!
小兰 快回答他呀
What is this?
什么嘛
You're always saying such nice things.
总是说些好听的话
Do you know that?
你知道吗
The lives of all the passengers are in my hands!
我的双手掌握着所有乘客的性命啊
Please don't talk like everything is fine!
拜托你别说得那么若无其事
You're never here when I need you.
关键时刻你总是不在
All I get is a phone call.
只有电话而已
Even when you come back, you disappear again in the next moment.
有时难得回来却又马上消失
Every time.
每次如此
I've had enough. I don't wanna hear it anymore!
我受够了 不想再听了
Shinichi-ni-chan said...
是新一哥哥说的
Ran, wait for me.
小兰 等我回来
Don't run away.
别逃走哦
I'll be back soon.
我马上就会回来的
You always leave me alone.
总是扔下我一个人
He said he hopes you'll wait for him to come back.
他说希望你能等他回来
What do you take me for?
你把我当成什么啊
I...
我…
I like you.
我喜欢你啊
Shinichi.
新一
Ran.
兰
Lights!
灯光
I see lights!
我看到灯光了
Red lights are moving like a ribbon!
红色的灯光像绸带般地在移动着
What?
什么
So that's it!
原来如此
Damn it, that bastard Kiddo!
可恶 臭基德
I won't let you escape!
休想逃跑
Kiddo is heading toward the pier!
基德往码头方向去了
Got it.
我知道了
Team A and B, take opposite sides and wrap around!
A B两组绕到另一侧包抄
Line up the patrol cars along the edges of the pier!
把警车沿码头边缘排开
Team C, follow my lead.
C组跟在我后面
We'll besiege Kiddo!
我要包围基德
Grandpa, there are so many patrol cars.
爷爷 有好多警车喔
Something must have happened.
可能是发生什么事了吧
It looks like they're coming this way.
好像往这边过来了
Ran, begin landing preparations!
小兰 准备降落
Those lights must be the patrol cars that Kiddo lured there.
那些光应该是基德引来的警车
So, that's why Kiddo jumped...
那么 基德跳下去是为了…
It was to use the lights from the patrol cars as a guide light for the runway.
为了利用警车的顶灯来做跑道的指引灯
That's my Kiddo-sama!
不愧是我的基德大人
I knew it!
我就知道
Ran, turn left and circle around once more.
小兰 再往左侧盘旋一次
Got it!
知道了
Kiddo, find Kiddo!
基德 快给我把基德找出来
He must be around here!
他一定在这附近
Find him!
快给我找
Did you find him?
找到没有
I didn't.
找不到
How's it going over there?
那边怎么样
The rest is up to you, Great Detective.
随后就交给你了 名侦探
All passengers.
各位乘客
This plane is going to make an emergency landing.
本机马上要实行紧急降落
Please fasten your seat belts.
请系好安全带
Follow the flight attendant's directions.
遵照乘务员的指示行动
Please take off your pens and eyeglasses.
请将笔或眼镜拿下
Place your high heeled shoes in your seatback pocket.
把高跟鞋放在座位上的袋子里
Lean forward.
身体向前倾
Place your head in between your legs.
将头放在两腿之间
Ran, be ready.
小兰 准备好了
Time to land.
就要降落了
What's the current altitude and speed?
现在的高度和速度是多少
Altitude: 700 feet. Speed: 140 knots.
高度700英尺 速度140节
Good. Keep the descent rate at 3 degrees.
很好 就这样保持3度的下降率
Sonoko.
园子
Lower the landing gear lever, pull the flap lever.
放下起落架杆 拉起襟翼杆
Landing gear? Flap?
起落架 襟翼
The landing gear lever is that one.
起落架杆是那个
The flap lever is over there.
襟翼杆在那边
Got it.
明白了
Lower the landing gear lever.
放下起落架杆
Pull up the flap lever.
拉起襟翼杆
What?
什么啊
What's wrong?
怎么了
Shinichi, I think we've run out of fuel.
新一 燃料好像已经用完了
Got it
我知道了
There is not a second chance.
没有重来的机会
We must make it this time.
必须一次成功
Inspector Megure...
目…目暮警官
That plane seems to be...
那架飞机好像…
It seems to be coming our way.
好像朝着我们这边过来了
Why?
为什么
Pull up the nose, and pull the thrust lever to the end!
拉起机首 推力杆用力拉到底
Everybody out of the way!
大家闪开
Bring the nose down!
机首向下
Reverse thrust!
逆向喷射
Stop! Stop! Stop!
停下来 停下来 停啊
Shinichi, there's a crane ahead!
新一 前面有起重机
We're going to hit it!
要撞上了
Damn it!
可恶
Rudder! Use your right foot to press the pedal!
方向舵 用右脚踩下踏板
It stopped.
停下来了
The plane has stopped!
飞机停下来了
Great!
太好了
Kudo-kun.
工藤
I guess you don't have it in your dictionary either, right?
看来你的字典上也没有啊
The word, impossible.
不可能这三个字
That's great, Ran-chan!
太好了 小兰姐姐
Ran-nee-chan!
小兰姐姐
Ran!
兰
Ran, hang in there!
兰 振作点
Sonoko?
园子
So they just passed out.
原来两人只是昏倒了啊
Not surprising.
这也难怪
It was really hard for you two this time.
这次真是难为你们了
Well done, Ran.
兰 干得漂亮
Blood pressure and pulse are normal.
血压 脉搏都很正常
You should be fine for now.
暂时应该没什么大碍了
But just in case, you should go to the hospital for a checkup.
不过以防万一你还是要到医院检查一次
Thank you.
谢谢
Is Sonoko okay?
请问园子她还好吗
She doesn't have any injuries.
她并没有受什么外伤
I think she fainted due to the shock.
应该是惊吓过度而昏倒了吧
I'm glad.
太好了
Please write down your name and address here.
麻烦在这里写上您的姓名以及住址
Okay.
好的
And your bust, waist and hip sizes.
还有你的胸围腰围和臀围的尺寸
That was really a beautiful landing.
刚才的着陆还真是大手笔啊
Kai... Kai...
怪…怪…
Well then, see you later.
那么先行别过 后会有期
Tell me your three sizes next time.
下次再告诉我你的三围吧
Kai... Kai...
怪…怪…
Hello?
喂
Ran, it's me.
小兰 是我
Shinichi?
新一
Hey...
你听我说
It wasn't you who called earlier, right?
刚才打电话来的不是新一你吧
I knew it.
我就知道
The Shinichi who called earlier was Kiddo.
刚才打电话来的新一也是基德扮的
I thought it was weird.
我就觉得怪怪的嘛
It was as if you were watching over me.
好像你就在我边上看着似的
Plus, in the middle of it, I heard Conan-kun's shout like "whoa'.
再加上中间还听到柯南哇的一声
Oh no.
糟糕
But at that point, Sonoko said that Kiddo had jumped off.
可是那时园子明明说基德已经跳下去了啊
In fact, I was quietly...
其实是我悄悄地…
I got it!
我知道了
So the one who jumped was Kiddo's assistant!
原来跳下去的是基德的手下啊
What?
什么
Kiddo must have disguised himself as someone and remained on the plane!
基德后来一定假扮成某人仍在飞机上
That's good!
太好了
That Shinichi is not you.
那个新一不是你
Not good at all.
一点也不好
That was close. It almost got out.
好险 差点泄露
What is it?
泄露什么啊
It's a secret between me and Kiddo.
这是我和基德之间的秘密
Tell me!
告诉我啦
No way!
才不
Why don't you deduce it? You're a detective, aren't you?
要不你推理看看啊 你不是侦探吗
How can I possibly deduce that?
这怎么可能推理得出来
Then wait until you arrest Kiddo and ask him.
那等你抓到基德后再去问他吧
You little...
你这家伙